# **Smit Patel**

# Full Stack Engineer

Winnipeg, Canada

△ smitpatelx.com

Github.com/smitpatelx

With over 4.5 years of experience working in the Software Industry with proficiencies in Javascript(ES6), Typescript, Python, GO, PHP, UI/UX, C#, Java and many more, I continue to be a driving force for my team. Seeking full time placement where I could deepen my existing knowledge and pick up on new rising tech.

# **Experience**

# **Lead Full Stack Engineer**

Datomar Labs Inc.

Mar 2022 - May 2023

Winnipeg, Manitoba

- O Work with the business unit to understand, develop or refine requirements for projects within the company.
- Manage UX and UI design and/or work with outside design stakeholders to ensure high quality design is implemented.
- -O- Build ci-cd pipelines, dockerize applications, setup projects, develop independently, research emerging technologies.
- Make use of technologies like React/Nextjs, MUI, Typescript, GO, PostgreSQL, Vuejs, Wordpress, TailwindCss, Headless UI and Framer Motion.
- -O- Work on optimizing, refactoring, analysis of code. Ensure good quality of testing and setup logging & analytics.

#### **Software Engineer**

Jan 2021 - Jan 2022

Farmlink Marketing Solutions

Winnipeg, Manitoba

- -O- Design, code and debug software applications using front end frameworks and enterprise applications
- **-O-** Performing Software analysis, requirements gathering, software reviews, identification of code metrics, system risk analysis, and software reliability analysis.
- -O- Writing tests, migrations, end-to-end feature testing and development using Python, Django, Postgres, Vuejs.
- -O- Mentor junior devs to meet code quality standards.
- -O- UI & UX design using figma, keeping up with latest technologies, design UI animations using leaflet and keyframes.

# **Director of Web Development**

June 2020 - Jan 2021

Blabbly

Winnipeg, Manitoba

- -O- Perform web development tasks utilizing PHP/NodeJs Framework, Web Services, and SQL Server.
- Design and evolve highly interactive user interfaces and HTML prototypes for web and email initiatives.

#### **Skills**

#### **Programming Languages**

Javascript (ES6), Typescript, Python, GO, PHP, C#, Java

#### **Libraries & Frameworks**

React, Nextjs, TainwindCss, MUI, Vuetify, Vuejs, Svelte, Framer Motion, Redux, Vuex, SCSS

#### **Database & Servers**

MySql, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, Firebase, Apache, Nginx, Linux, Docker, AWS, GCS, Heroku

#### Other

Git, JSP, CertBot, Bootstrap, Foundation, Ulkit

#### **Tools & Softwares**

AdobeXD, Figma, AdobeAi, SEO, Agile, Jira, Sentry, Gleap, VS Code, Go Land, Blender

# **Education**

## **Computer Programmer**

Durham College Oshawa, ON 2017-2020

# **Certifications**

- MVC with Laravel
- OOP with C#
- Deployment with Docker
- Accessibility for web
- Advance CSS and Key Frames
- -- Reactis Advance Concepts
- Vuejs Master Class
- Nextjs FullStack
- Websocket for modern Apps
- -- Flutter mobile development

# **Experience**

#### **Director of Web Development**

Blabbly

June 2020 - Jan 2021 Winnipeg, Manitoba

- O Work as part of an agile team fostering teamwork, mentoring others, and striving for overall excellence.
- -O- Develop & Design custom solutions like plugins, theme & CI-CD pipeline for corporate clients.
- -O- Setup C-Panels, Configure Docker Mail Serves & Micro-services using Kubernetes for various applications.

#### Full-Stack Developer

Oct 2017 - Mar 2020

Self-Employed

Toronto, Ontario

- -O- Building Backend API using Node.js, PHP, ASP.NET, JAVA to serve requests and server content on front-end.
- Setup containers on Debian based systems to host Nginx and Apache servers.
- -O- Setup docker containers for Postgres, MySql and MongoDB to improve stability and scalability of projects.
- -O- Develop UI/UX by using tools like AdobeXD, Figma and collobrate with other developers to improve design.
- -O- Prototype responsive websites using Nuxt.js; design interactions using SCSS, TailwindCss and BootStrap.

# Projects I worked on

#### **Grainfox - Marketing solutions for** farmers

https://www.farmlinksolutions.ca/what-is-grainfox/

Django Vue.js Leafletjs Fusion Charts

#### Site Notes

https://site-notes.smitpatelx.com/

React React-Query Fastapi-Py SqlAlchemy

Docker Postgresql Pydantic Redis

#### Open Source plugin for wordpress

**Code**: https://github.com/smitpatelx/robust-user-search/ Plugin: https://wordpress.org/plugins/robust-user-search/

PHP Vue3 Tailwindcss Vite

#### **DEUTZ - Build & Price tool for** automobile industry

https://deutz.preproduction.datomar.dev/build-price/

React Next.js GO MUI TypeScript

# Mufflr - A car buying service

https://app.mufflr.ca

React Next.js Tailwindcss GO Heroku

#### **Brownie Points**

https://browniepoints.club/

Vue.js SCSS Bulma Shepherd Js

# Clicknow - Link shortener & Analytics

https://clicknow.cc/

React React-Query GO SqlBoiler

SqlMigrator PostgreSql Redis

### String Utils (NPM)

https://www.npmjs.com/package/@smitpatelx/string-utils

Typescript Nx Jest Github Actions

#### Halcyon - Contact form api https://github.com/smitpatelx/halcyon

Express Mongo Docker JWT

#### Real-Estate Listing - Avenest https://github.com/smitpatelx/avenest

Vue.js PHP TailwindCss PostgreSql

# **Real-Time Chat Application**

https://github.com/smitpatelx/socket\_chat

Nodejs Vue.js Socket.io

#### Knock-Knock jokebot api https://github.com/smitpatelx/knock-knock

(Python) (Django) (Sqlite) (Docker)